<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- Home -->
    <string name="app_name">BoardingDraft</string>
    <string name="bouton_lancer_vote">Vote</string>
    <string name="bouton_liste_jeux">List of games</string>
    <string name="texte_liste_joueurs">Players present:</string>
    <string name="texte_saisie_nom_joueur">Enter player name</string>

    <!-- Voting fragment -->
    <string name="titre_fragment_vote">Vote</string>
    <string name="texte_en_cours_de_construction">Page is under construction. Here are some pictures of our feline friends to keep you waiting.</string>
    <string name="texte_toast_pas_internet">Please connect to the internet to view the images.</string>

    <!-- Games fragment -->
    <string name="titre_fragment_jeux">Games</string>
    <!-- Game titles -->
    <string name="titre_jeu_UNO">UNO</string>
    <string name="titre_jeu_president">President</string>
    <string name="titre_jeu_bonne_paye">The good pay</string>
    <string name="titre_jeu_petits_chevaux">The little horses</string>
    <string name="titre_jeu_mikado">Mikado</string>
    <string name="titre_jeu_oie">The game of the goose</string>
    <string name="titre_jeu_phase_10">Stage 10</string>
    <!-- Game Descriptions -->
    <string name="desc_jeu_UNO">Carefully shuffle the cards and deal the same number to each player.
        Make a pile with the rest of the cards, face down: this will constitute THE DRAW PILE.
        Turn over the top card of the draw pile, to place it face up next to the draw pile,
        to start LE TALON. This map will serve as a starting point.
        The starting player must cover the top card of the stock pile with a card of the same suit,
        or bearing the same number or the same symbol as it. For example, if the top card of the stock
        is a red 7, he can play any red card or a 7 of any suit.
        He can also play a JOKER card.
        If the player does not have any cards offering one of these possibilities, he must then draw the top card
        from the draw pile. If this card can be played, then he can play it immediately by placing it on his stock;
        otherwise he passes his turn, obviously keeping this additional card.
        The player who gets rid of all his cards first is the winner of the round. We establish the scores of this round
        and we then start the next round.</string>
    <string name="desc_jeu_president">The \"president\", also called \"asshole\", is a card game
        played with four or more players, with a deck of 32 or 54 cards.
        The goal of each player is to get rid of all their cards as quickly as possible.
        The players who were the fastest to get rid of their cards are entitled to an advantage for the next game
        and conversely the slowest will be penalized by a handicap. The interest of this game is therefore to chain several
        games in a row in order to see the players evolve in the classification.
        As the game progresses, the relative strength of the cards is in this order (from weakest to strongest):
        3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, Jack, Queen, King, Ace, 2 and, if applicable, Joker.
        If a game is played with a reduced number of cards (32 cards for 4 players and 30 cards for 3 players), it is preferable to apply
        the order: 8, 9, 10, Jack, Queen, King, Ace, 7.</string>
    <string name="desc_jeu_bonne_paye">Players take turns rolling a dice to move around the course. Depending on the square where they fall,
        they have to draw a card, pay or receive money.
        Each box is a day of the month, and at the end of the month, players receive their pay and must settle their bills.
        The object of the game is to be the player with the most money (or the others to run out), using different methods.</string>
    <string name="desc_jeu_petits_chevaux">The \"little horses\" game is a game that consists of moving several pawns
        (known as horses) per player (between 1 and 3 per player in general), and to take them to the part reserved for their color.
        The first player to reach the last triangular square wins the game.
        Two to four players each have one or more horse pawns, and play by rolling a dice in turn.
        A player must first roll a 6 with the dice in order to take a horse out of his stable. He must then make it go through
        all the squares located at the periphery of the board, moving it forward a number of squares equal to the result of the die.
        Pawns are advanced clockwise.
        There are different special cases. Thus, when a horse arrives on a square occupied by a competitor, he sends him back to his stable (the start).
        On the other hand, if the player arrives on a square occupied by another horse of his color, he stops his pawn just behind it.
        Finally, a 6 obtained on the dice allows replay.
        After his pawn has gone around the board, the player must make the exact number on the die so that he stops in front of his staircase.
        For example, if the horse pawn is located three spaces from the bottom of the stairs, the player must roll a 3 on his die to
        take his pawn down the stairs. If the number is too big, he moves his pawn to the bottom square of the stairs,
        then moves it back the number of squares corresponding to the difference between the figure to be made and the figure made; taking the example:
        if the player rolls a 4, he will move the pawn three spaces forward, then move it back one space.
        Once a player\'s pawn is in the space in front of the stairs of his color,
        he must go up step by step to the center of the game. For this, the player must obtain each time the exact figure
        entered in the box, and a 6 to reach the cut.
        Victory is won by the first player who manages to bring, depending on the variant, one or more of his horse-pawns to the cup.
        Each player is free to bring out the number of horses he wishes, but he can only move one horse per turn.</string>
    <string name="desc_jeu_mikado">\"Mikado\" is a game of skill, played by 2 to 6 players. It consists of a set of chopsticks,
        about 20 cm long and tapered at the ends, which are dropped so that they become entangled, before removing them,
        one by one, without moving the others.
        There are many variants of Mikado, so the values and colors mentioned are purely indicative. A game usually consists of the following pieces:
        1 Mikado chopsticks, worth 20 points (black color)
        5 Samurai chopsticks, worth 10 points each (yellow color)
        5 Mandarin chopsticks, worth 5 points each (blue color)
        15 Bonze chopsticks, worth 3 points each (green color)
        15 Coolie chopsticks, worth 2 points each (color red)
        Before starting the game, the sticks are held clenched in the fist and they are dropped, fanned out, on a table or on the ground.
        Each player must then remove a stick of their choice. Under no circumstances should he touch or move another chopsticks.
        As long as he succeeds, he can continue to remove other wands. As soon as he inadvertently moves another chopsticks,
        he yields his turn to the next player.
        At the end of the game, the winner is the one who has accumulated the most points.
        It is often possible to use a chopsticks that has already been retrieved to remove another.
        In some variants, this possibility is nevertheless reserved for the Mikado chopsticks only.</string>
    <string name="desc_jeu_oie">The \"game of the goose\" is a parlor game where pawns are moved according to the results of two dice.
         Traditionally, this game of pure chance comprises 63 squares arranged in an inwardly wound spiral with a number of traps.
         The goal is to get to the last square first.</string>
    <string name="desc_jeu_phase_10">\"Phase 10\" is a sort of evolved \"Rummy\", with simple and clever rules.
        The fundamental difference is the 10 phases. You must, round after round, perform these 10 compulsory figures in order:
        1 : 2 sets
        2 : 1 set + 1 suite of 4
        3 : 1 square + 1 suite of 4
        4 : 1 suite of 7
        5 : 1 suite of 8
        6 : 1 suite of 9
        7 : 2 squares
        8 : 7 cards of the same color
        9 : 1 poker + 1 pair
        10 : 1 poker + 1 set
        The game consists of 108 cards: 2 x (1 to 12 in 4 colors), 4 x "skip a turn", and 8 jokers.
        In the first round, all players must perform phase 1, i.e. 2 sets. As soon as a player has played all his cards,
        the round is over. All players score negative points, depending on the cards left in their hand,
        then we attack the next round. All those who have succeeded in their current phase then move on to the next phase.
        The others restart the phase in which they failed.
        The phases being of increasing difficulty, late players can catch up with their opponents.</string>

</resources>